ARE YOU READY, KIDS?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
孩子们：
是的，是的，队长！
I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
我听不到你说话。
( louder ):
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
（大声）：
是的，是的，队长！
* OH...
* 哦...
* WHO LIVES IN A PINEAPPLE
UNDER THE SEA? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
* 海绵宝宝！
* ABSORBENT AND YELLOW
AND POROUS IS HE. *
* 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的。 *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
* 海绵宝宝！
* IF NAUTICAL NONSENSE BE
SOMETHING YOU WISH... *
*如果航海废话是
您想要的东西... *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
* 海绵宝宝！
* THEN DROP ON THE DECK
AND FLOP LIKE A FISH. *
* 然后掉到甲板上
像鱼一样扑通扑通。 *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
* 海绵宝宝！
* READY?
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS! *
* 准备好？
海绵宝宝！ *
* SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
* 海绵宝宝！
( laughs heartily )
（会心地笑）
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
( plays airy tune )
[字幕由THE赞助
美国教育部
（演奏轻快的曲调）
and NICKELODEON]
和尼克频道]
( sizzling )
（铁板）
( loud buzzing )
（大声嗡嗡声）
( all pop to life
and commence buzzing )
（一切都栩栩如生
并开始发出嗡嗡声）
( pop )
（ 流行音乐 ）
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
Krabs:
SPONGEBOB! SPONGEBOB!
螃蟹：
海绵宝宝！海绵宝宝！
WAKE UP, BOY!
醒醒吧，孩子！
YOU'RE BURNING
ME MONEY!
你正在燃烧
我的钱！
( alarm sounds,
SpongeBob yelps )
（警报声响起，
海绵宝宝尖叫）
MR. KRABS, WHAT DO WE DO?
先生。蟹蟹，我们该怎么办？
HERE, USE THIS.
在这里，使用这个。
( grunts )
（咕哝声）
( clang )
（叮当）
( flames whoosh )
（火焰呼啸）
( both whine in fear )
（两人都因恐惧而哀嚎）
( blowing frantically )
（疯狂地吹）
( teeth chattering )
（牙齿打颤）
( imitating fire alarm )
（模仿火警）
( gurgling )
（咕噜声）
HOORAY!
万岁！
( steam whistling )
（蒸汽呼啸）
( sizzles )
（嘶嘶声）
SPONGEBOB, COME
INTO ME OFFICE.
海绵宝宝，来吧
进入我的办公室。
WHAT'S WRONG, BOY?
出了什么问题，男孩？
WELL, I...
嗯，我...
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME
这是第四次
I'VE HAD TO SCRAPE YOU
OFF OF SOMETHING.
我不得不刮你
离开某事。
WELL, I'VE BEEN THINKING.
嗯，我一直在想。
WE NEED TO GET YOU
THINKING ABOUT WORK.
我们需要找到你
思考工作。
NO OFFENSE, MR. KRABS,
BUT I'VE BEEN THINKING
无意冒犯，先生。螃蟹，
但我一直在想
ABOUT GIVING UP
MY COLD INDUSTRIAL LIFE
关于放弃
我冰冷的工业生活
IN FAVOR OF
A MORE NATURAL
有利于
更自然
AND FREE LIFE
AMONG THE JELLYFISH.
和自由的生活
水母之中。
( laughs heartily )
（会心地笑）
( laughter echoes )
（笑声回响）
AH... SPONGEBOB,
YOU WOULDN'T LAST
啊...海绵宝宝，
你不会长久的
EVEN ONE DAY
IN THE WILD.
即使有一天
在野外。
THIS IS YOUR
NATURAL HABITAT.
这是你的
自然栖息地。
THIS IS YOUR
WIDE-OPEN RANGE.
这是你的
范围广泛。
THESE ARE
YOUR AMBER WAVES.
这些是
你的琥珀色波浪。
AND THIS... OH, THIS
IS YOUR GOLDEN SCEPTER
还有这个...哦，这个
是你的金权杖吗
WITH WHICH YOU RULE!
由你来统治！
THAT'S BETTER THAN NASTY OLD
JELLYFISH, RIGHT, SPONGEBOB?
这比肮脏的旧的要好
水母，对吧，海绵宝宝？
SPONGEBOB?
海绵宝宝？
OH, I CAN TOO
LAST MORE THAN ONE DAY.
哦，我也可以
持续超过一天。
I'LL SHOW HIM.
我会告诉他。
AW, BARNACLES!
哇，藤壶！
SPONGEBOB, WAIT.
海绵宝宝，等等。
( screams )
（尖叫声）
OH, HE'LL BE BACK,
ALL RIGHT.
哦，他会回来的，
好吧。
HE'LL BE BACK.
他会回来的。
AND, SQUIDWARD
还有，章鱼哥
I WANT YOU TO HAVE
MY CAN OPENER.
我希望你有
我的开罐器。
AND I THOUGHT
THIS FRIENDSHIP
WOULD NEVER PAY OFF.
我想
这份友谊
永远不会有回报。
ARE... ARE... ARE...
是……是……是……
ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT
TO GIVE ME THIS MAYONNAISE?
你确定要吗
给我这个蛋黄酱？
IT'S ALL YOURS.
都是你的。
AND THESE
OLD PHONE BOOKS?
还有这些
旧电话簿？
ALL YOURS, OLD FRIEND.
都是你的，老朋友。
PATRICK, THERE IS
ONE MORE THING
帕特里克，有
还有一件事
I WANT YOU TO HAVE.
我希望你拥有。
( gasps )
（喘气）
( panting with excitement )
（激动得气喘吁吁）
OL' RELIABLE?!
可靠吗？！
( sobs )
（抽泣）
HOWDY, Y'ALL.
大家好。
HEY, SPONGEBOB, YOU
HAVING A GARAGE SALE?
嘿，海绵宝宝，你
正在进行车库拍卖吗？
NO, SANDY, I'M GIVING UP
MY MATERIAL POSSESSIONS
不，桑迪，我放弃
我的物质财富
TO LIVE IN THE WILD
WITH THE JELLYFISH.
野外生活
与水母。
SPONGEBOB, OF
ALL THE CRAZY SCHEMES
海绵宝宝
所有疯狂的计划
WHY WOULD YOU WANT TO LIVE
AMONG THE JELLYFISH?
你为什么想活下去
属于水母吗？
THEY'RE COLD AND MEAN
AND NONE TOO BRIGHT.
他们冷酷刻薄
而且不太亮。
OH, SANDY, THAT'S EXACTLY
THE RESPONSE I WOULD EXPECT
哦，桑迪，正是如此
我期望的回应
FROM SOMEONE WHO LIVES
THE SHAM OF A LIFE
I ONCE LIVED.
来自活着的人
人生的骗局
我曾经活过。
I'LL PROVE I DON'T NEED
THIS STUFF TO BE HAPPY.
我会证明我不需要
这件事让你快乐。
MAYBE SOMEDAY YOU'LL
WISE UP AND JOIN ME.
也许有一天你会
清醒一点，加入我吧。
GOOD-BYE.
再见。
( pop )
（ 流行音乐 ）
I WON'T BE NEEDING THESE.
我不需要这些。
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ...
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声......
HE TOOK OFF
HIS PANTS.
他起飞了
他的裤子。
I'LL GIVE HIM
A WEEK.
我会给他
一周。
I'LL GIVE HIM
11 MINUTES.
我会给他
11 分钟。
PATRICK SAD!
帕特里克伤心！
I'M HOME.
我回来了。
I'M HOME! I'M HOME!
我回来了！我回来了！
I'M HOME, I'M HOME, I'M HOME,
I'M HOME, I'M HOME, I'M HOME
我回家了，我回家了，我回家了，
我回家了，我回家了，我回家了
I'M HOME, I'M HOME!
我回来了，我回来了！
( sudden buzzing )
（突然嗡嗡声）
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
WAIT FOR ME.
兄弟姐妹们，
等我。
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ.
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声。
OKAY, I'M HERE.
好的，我在这儿。
WAIT, I JUST GOT HERE.
等等，我刚到这里。
MY JELLYFISH INSTINCTS
TELL ME TO GO...
我的水母本能
告诉我走...
( slurps )
（啜饮）
( pops )
（流行音乐）
THAT WAY.
那样。
* BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ,
BUZZ, BUZZ... *
* 嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声...*
( jellyfish buzzing )
（水母嗡嗡声）
( chomping )
（咀嚼）
( gags )
（笑声）
MMM, THIS IS THE LIFE.
嗯，这就是生活。
HEY, EVERYBODY,
BUZZ, BUZZ.
嘿，大家，
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声。
BUZZ TO YOU.
向您发出嗡嗡声。
BUZZ, BUZZ.
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声。
NICE CURRENT TODAY.
今天电流不错。
HEY, WHAT'S THE BUZZ?
嘿，有什么动静？
HELLO, I'M JELLYBOB--
AND YOU ARE...?
你好，我是果冻——
而你是……？
( electricity crackles )
（电流噼啪声）
UH... NICE TO MEET YOU.
呃...很高兴认识你。
( sniffing )
（嗅）
MMM.
嗯。
HERE, PATRICK,
HAVE A KRABBY PATTY.
在这里，帕特里克，
来一份蟹肉饼吧。
( choking up )
（哽咽）
THERE HE IS, PATRICK.
他在那里，帕特里克。
SAY YOUR LINE.
说出你的台词。
"WHY, THANK YOU, SANDY.
“为什么，谢谢你，桑迪。
"I WOULD LOVE ONE.
“我想要一个。
"(TAKE PATTY).
“（带上帕蒂）。
"TOO BAD SPONGEBOB
ISN'T HERE.
“海绵宝宝太糟糕了
不在这里。
"THESE ARE HIS FAVORITES.
“这些是他的最爱。
"I SURE WISH HE'D COME HOME.
“我当然希望他能回家。
(TAKE BITE)."
（咬一口）。”
I CAN'T DO IT!
我做不到！
SPONGEBOB!
海绵宝宝！
COME BACK!
回来！
PATRICK, I'M NOT COMING HOME.
帕特里克，我不会回家。
I MISS YOU.
我想你。
SANDY MISSES YOU.
桑迪想念你。
EVEN SQUIDWARD MISSES YOU.
就连章鱼哥也想念你。
WHOOPEE!
哇哦！
( party music playing )
（派对音乐播放）
I'M HAPPY HERE.
我在这里很高兴。
THIS IS MY HOME NOW.
现在这是我的家。
( Sandy grunting )
（桑迪咕哝）
( sobbing )
（抽泣）
SPONGEBOB!
海绵宝宝！
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
HEY, EVERYBODY, I'M BACK.
嘿，大家好，我回来了。
I THINK I'M GETTING
THE HANG OF THIS.
我想我得到了
这其中的窍门。
( panting heavily )
（气喘吁吁）
PATRICK, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
帕特里克，你在做什么？
IF I CAN'T HAVE YOU AS A FRIEND,
I'M GOING TO MAKE YOU A TROPHY.
如果我不能把你当朋友，
我要为你制作一座奖杯。
I EVEN PICKED OUT
THIS NICE JAR FOR YOU.
我什至挑选了
这个漂亮的罐子送给你。
PATRICK, GO HOME.
帕特里克，回家吧。
I'M A JELLYFISH NOW.
我现在是水母了。
( gurgling cry )
（咯咯的哭声）
( panting )
（气喘吁吁）
WOW!
哇！
( continues gurgling cry)
（继续咯咯的哭声）
Patrick:
I CAN SEE YOU
THERE.
帕特里克：
我能看到你
那里。
I STILL SEE YOU.
我仍然见到你。
YOU'RE GOING
TO LOOK GOOD
ON MY MANTEL.
你要去
看起来不错
在我的壁炉架上。
FRIENDS FOREVER,
SPONGEBOB!
永远的朋友，
海绵宝宝！
( panting slowing down )
（气喘吁吁的速度减慢）
AHH.
啊啊。
I GOT YOU NOW, SPONGEBOB.
我现在找到你了，海绵宝宝。
( straining )
（用力）
PATRICK, NO!
帕特里克，不！
( SpongeBob panting,
Patrick yelling)
（海绵宝宝气喘吁吁，
帕特里克大喊）
( grunting )
（咕哝）
OKAY!
好的！
SO THIS IS THE WAY
IT'S GOING TO BE.
所以这就是方法
一定会的。
I HOPE YOU'RE HAPPY.
我希望你快乐。
( groans )
（呻吟）
WELL, THAT'S OVER.
好了，结束了。
BACK TO JELLYFISH MATTERS.
回到水母问题。
( drip )
（滴）
MMM, JELLY.
嗯，果冻。
( buzzing )
（嗡嗡声）
AH, MY JELLYFISH BRETHREN
ARE RETURNING.
啊，我的水母兄弟
即将回归。
GREETINGS, COMRADES.
同志们，你们好。
( electricity crackles.
SpongeBob screams )
（电流噼啪作响。
海绵宝宝尖叫）
( screaming )
（尖叫）
OW! OOH! OW! OW!
噢！哦！噢！噢！
BEING A JELLYFISH SURE IS FUN.
成为水母确实很有趣。
BUZZ... BUZZ...
嗡嗡……嗡嗡……
( crack )
（ 裂缝 ）
BUZZ.
嗡嗡声。
( shivering )
（发抖）
( pop )
（ 流行音乐 ）
( resumes shivering )
（又开始发抖）
HEY!
嘿！
EW, I'M ITCHY.
EW，我很痒。
ITCHY-- WHY AM I SO ITCHY?
痒——为什么我这么痒？
( screams )
（尖叫声）
POISON SEA URCHINS.
毒海胆。
OW, OW, ITCH, ITCH,
ITCH, ITCH, OW
噢，噢，痒，痒，
痒，痒，噢
OOH, OW, OW, OW, ITCH, ITCH,
ITCH, ITCH, ITCH, ITCH...
噢，噢，噢，噢，痒，痒，
痒，痒，痒，痒……
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ,
BUZZ, BUZZ
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ,
BUZZ, BUZZ...
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声，
嗡嗡声，嗡嗡声……
( thud )
（砰）
( muffled ):
KRABBY PATTIES.
（低声）：
蟹肉饼。
BUZZ...
嗡嗡声...
( sniffs )
（嗅）
BUZZ...
嗡嗡声...
( sniffs )
（嗅）
SANDY...
沙...
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ...
嗡嗡声、嗡嗡声、嗡嗡声……
( sniffs )
（嗅）
BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ, BUZZ...
嗡嗡声、嗡嗡声、嗡嗡声、嗡嗡声……
WHAT HAVE I DONE?
我做了什么？
I HAD A GREAT LIFE AND FRIENDS,
AND I GAVE ALL OF THAT UP.
我有美好的生活和朋友，
我放弃了这一切。
All:
WELCOME HOME, SPONGEBOB!
全部：
欢迎回家，海绵宝宝！
YOU GUYS ARE THE BEST.
你们是最棒的。
I MADE A HUGE MISTAKE.
我犯了一个巨大的错误。
PLEASE FORGIVE ME.
请原谅我。
AH, QUIT YOUR BLUBBERING
AND HAVE A KRABBY PATTY.
啊，别哭了
还有蟹肉饼。
DON'T MIND
IF I DO.
不介意
如果我这样做的话。
AND I'LL SEE YOU AT WORK
我会在工作中见到你
FIRST THING
TOMORROW MORNING.
第一件事
明天早上。
AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
是的，是的，队长！
SPONGEBOB, DO US
ALL A FAVOR...
海绵宝宝，我们一起吧
一切都好...
DON'T MIND IF I DO.
如果我这样做，请不要介意。
( snaps pants loudly )
（大声拍裤子）
TA-DAH!
达达！
AW.
艾沃。
OKAY, THAT'S ENOUGH.
好了，够了。
( growls
affectionately )
（咆哮
深情地）
( all ooh and ahh )
（所有哦和啊）
( meows )
（喵）
COULD WE PLEASE
STOP THIS?
我们可以吗？
停止这个？
PATRICK ITCHY.
帕特里克发痒。
All:
OOH! OW! OH! OW! OOH!
全部：
哦！噢！哦！噢！哦！
IT IS GREAT
TO BE HOME!
太棒了
回家！
( crowing )
（啼叫）
( snoring )
（打鼾）
( SpongeBob and Patrick
jabbering )
（海绵宝宝和帕特里克
喋喋不休）
HUH?
嗯？
( jabbering stops )
（叽叽喳喳的声音停止了）
( jabbering resumes )
（喋喋不休地继续）
HUH?!
啊？！
( blows noisemaker )
（吹响噪音）
Both:
SURPRISE!
两者：
惊喜！
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, SQUIDWARD!
生日快乐，章鱼哥！
* HAPPY, HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
* 生日快乐！
* HAPPY BIRTHDAY CAKE!
* 生日蛋糕快乐！
* HAPPY, HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
* 生日快乐！
* PIN THE TAIL
ON THE SEA HORSE! *
* 固定尾巴
在海马上！ *
* HAPPY, HAPPY BIRTHDAY!
* 生日快乐！
* HAPPY BIRTHDAY, SQUIDWARD!
*生日快乐，章鱼哥！
( SpongeBob cheering,
noisemakers blaring )
（海绵宝宝欢呼，
噪音制造者发出刺耳的声音）
SpongeBob:
SO LONG, SQUIDWARD,
BYE-BYE.
海绵宝宝：
再见，章鱼哥，
再见。
DON'T DO ANYTHING
I WOULDN'T DO.
什么都不要做
我不会这么做。
Patrick:
ANOTHER YEAR OLDER.
帕特里克：
又老了一岁。
IT'S NOT MY BIRTHDAY!
这不是我的生日！
THAT'S IT!
就是这样！
I'M MOVING OUT
OF THIS NEIGHBORHOOD.
我要搬出去
这个街区的。
Realtor:
ABSOLUTELY, MR. TENTACLES.
房地产经纪人：
绝对可以，先生。触手。
I CAN SELL YOUR HOME
IN A HEARTBEAT.
我可以卖掉你的房子
一瞬间。
OH, THAT'S GREAT NEWS
哦，这是个好消息
BECAUSE I WANT TO MOVE
AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
因为我想搬家
尽快。
NO PROBLEM... AS LONG AS IT'S
NOT INFESTED WITH NEMATODES
没问题...只要它
未感染线虫
OR SURROUNDED
BY TROUBLESOME NEIGHBORS
或被包围
惹麻烦的邻居
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
或者类似的东西。
OH, SURE, THERE'S NONE OF THAT.
哦，当然，没有这些。
DID YOU SAY NEIGHBORS?
你说的是邻居吗？
Of course! I can't tell you
当然！我不能告诉你
how many times
I've seen a sale fall through
多少次
我看到销售失败了
because of bad neighbors.
因为邻居不好。
NEIGHBORS, UH...
邻居们，呃……
ANYWAY, I'LL BE BY TOMORROW
TO CHECK OUT THE HOUSE.
不管怎样，我明天就到
检查房子。
SEE YOU THEN.
到时候见。
SPONGEBOB.
海绵宝宝。
NO ONE WILL EVER BUY MY HOUSE
WITH HIM LIVING NEXT DOOR.
没有人会买我的房子
他住在隔壁。
WHATEVER A GOOD NEIGHBOR
WOULD DO, HE DOES THE OPPOSITE.
无论如何都是好邻居
会做，他却做相反的事。
OPPOSITE... OPPOSITE.
对面……对面。
( rooster crowing )
（公鸡打鸣）
( cacophonous music playing )
( yells )
（刺耳的音乐播放）
（大喊）
( playing loudly )
（大声播放）
UH, SQUIDWARD...
呃，章鱼哥……
WHY ARE YOU
PLAYING THE DRUM?
你为什么
打鼓？
DRUM?
鼓？
WHAT DRUM?
什么鼓？
THIS IS JUST
MY WIG CASE, SEE?
这只是
我的假发盒，看到了吗？
( cackles )
（咯咯笑）
COME ON, SPONGEBOB, TACKLE ME!
来吧，海绵宝宝，来对付我吧！
SQUIDWARD, YOU NEED BED REST.
章鱼哥，你需要卧床休息。
I'LL KEEP
YOU SAFE
我会保留
你安全了
UNTIL YOU'RE
WELL AGAIN.
直到你
又好。
OH, I GET IT.
哦，我明白了。
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT
DAY IT IS, DO YOU?
你不知道什么
今天是，你呢？
UH, WEDNESDAY?
呃，星期三？
WHY, IT'S OPPOSITE DAY.
为什么，今天是相反的一天。
YOU'VE NEVER HEARD OF IT?
您从未听说过吗？
BOY, HAVE YOU BEEN MISSING OUT.
男孩，你错过了吗？
OPPOSITE DAY IS
THE ONE DAY
OF THE YEAR
对面的日子是
有一天
年度最佳
WHEN YOU GET
TO ACT DIFFERENT.
当你得到
采取不同的行动。
NORMALLY I'M
STUFFY AND BORING
通常我是
闷闷不乐
BUT TODAY I'M SILLY
AND SPONTANEOUS.
但今天我很傻
而且是自发的。
( giggles )
（咯咯笑）
DOES EVERYBODY KNOW
ABOUT OPPOSITE DAY?
大家都知道吗
关于相反的日子？
OH, SURE.
哦，当然。
IT'S A GAME, GET IT?
这是一个游戏，明白吗？
OH, A GAME.
哦，一场游戏。
YEAH.
是的。
NORMALLY, YOU'RE
REALLY LOUD AND ANNOYING
通常情况下，你是
真的很吵而且很烦人
SO WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO BE TODAY?
那么你是什么
今天会吗？
QUIET AND OUT OF THE WAY.
安静且不碍事。
YAY!
耶！
YEAH.
是的。
WHY DON'T YOU GET A JUMP ON IT.
为什么不立即行动起来呢？
( exuberantly ):
I LOVE...
（兴高采烈地）：
我爱...
( gruffly ):
I MEAN, I HATE
OPPOSITE DAY.
（粗声粗气）：
我的意思是，我讨厌
相反的一天。
( giggles )
（咯咯笑）
( yelling ):
I'M NOT READY.
（大喊）：
我还没准备好。
SO LONG, CHUM.
再见，密友。
AND GOOD-BYE, BIKINI BOTTOM.
再见，比基尼泳裤。
( door slams )
（关门声）
GARY, IT'S OPPOSITE DAY
AND I'M--
加里，今天是相反的一天
而我——
WALK, DON'T RUN--
走路，不要跑——
AND I'M GOING TO...
我要去...
OPPOSITE, OPPOSITE.
相反，相反。
I'M JUST GOING TO CRAWL INTO BED
AND DO NOTHING ALL DAY.
我只是要爬上床
并且整天什么也不做。
TOO BAD IT ONLY COMES
ONCE A YEAR, HUH, GARY?
可惜它只来了
一年一次，嗯，加里？
( meows )
（喵）
GARY, WHERE'S
YOUR HOLIDAY SPIRIT?
加里，在哪里
您的假期精神如何？
( barks )
（吠叫）
( doorbell rings )
（门铃响了）
COMPANY!
公司！
I HATE COMPANY.
我讨厌有人陪伴。
WHO'S THERE?
谁在那儿？
IT'S PATRICK.
这是帕特里克。
PATRICK... GO AWAY!
帕特里克……走开！
I NEVER WANT TO SEE YOU AGAIN!
我再也不想见到你了！
( giggles )
（咯咯笑）
( whimpers )
（呜咽）
( sobbing )
（抽泣）
SPONGEBOB DOESN'T
LIKE ME ANYMORE.
海绵宝宝没有
不再喜欢我了。
THAT'S RIGHT.
这是正确的。
YOU'RE MY WORST ENEMY.
你是我最大的敌人。
( sobbing )
（抽泣）
PATRICK, YOU'RE NOT
REALLY NOT MY FRIEND.
帕特里克，你不是
真的不是我的朋友。
IT'S JUST OPPOSITE DAY.
这只是相反的一天。
OPPOSITE DAY?
对面的日子？
HEY, I'VE
HEARD OF THAT.
嘿，我已经
听说过。
YOU HAVE?
你有吗？
NO, WHAT IS IT?
不，这是什么？
WELL, WHATEVER
YOU NORMALLY DO
好吧，无论如何
你通常会这样做
TODAY YOU DO
THE OPPOSITE.
今天你做到了
相反。
LET ME TRY,
LET ME TRY.
让我试试，
让我试试。
( straining )
（用力）
( still straining )
（还在紧张）
PATRICK!
帕特里克！
PATRICK, BREATHE!
帕特里克，呼吸！
( exhales loudly )
（大声呼气）
( gasping )
（喘气）
NOT THAT OPPOSITE.
并非相反。
LET ME SHOW YOU HOW TO DO IT...
THE WRONG WAY.
让我告诉你怎么做......
错误的方式。
MEOW.
喵。
( speaking gibberish )
（胡言乱语）
( laughing )
（笑）
SAY, WANT TO HELP ME
说，想帮助我
DO SOME WORK
AROUND THE HOUSE,
WORST ENEMY?
做一些工作
在房子周围，
最坏的敌人？
NOPE.
没有。
( laughing )
（笑）
( Squidward cackles )
（章鱼哥咯咯笑）
NEARLY NOON
AND NOT A PEEP FROM SPONGEBOB.
接近中午
而不是海绵宝宝的窥视。
I'M ALMOST SORRY I'M LEAVING.
我几乎要后悔我要离开了。
( cackles )
（咯咯笑）
OPPOSITE DAY.
相反的一天。
( crashing )
（崩溃）
SPONGEBOB, WHAT ARE YOU...?
海绵宝宝，你是什么……？
( yells )
（大喊）
HELLO, SQUIDWARD.
你好，章鱼哥。
OOP, I MEAN,
GOOD-BYE, SQUIDWARD.
哦，我的意思是，
再见，章鱼哥。
ISN'T OPPOSITE DAY... TERRIBLE.
对面的日子不是……太可怕了。
( laughs )
（笑）
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT'S TERRIBLE:
LIVING NEXT TO YOU.
我会告诉你什么是可怕的：
住在您旁边。
YOU'RE THE
WORST NEIGHBOR
IN HISTORY.
你就是
最坏的邻居
在历史上。
WOW! THAT'S THE NICEST THING
SQUIDWARD HAS EVER SAID TO ME.
哇！这是最好的事情
章鱼哥曾经对我说过。
IF THE REAL ESTATE AGENT
SEES THAT MESS
如果房地产经纪人
看到那乱七八糟的东西
I'LL NEVER SELL THIS HOUSE.
我永远不会卖掉这房子。
Patrick:
ISN'T IT BEAUTIFUL?
帕特里克：
不是很漂亮吗？
ON OPPOSITE DAY IT IS.
相反的一天。
( rumbling )
（隆隆声）
OUT OF THE WAY, SPONGEBOB!
让开，海绵宝宝！
( hammer pounding )
（锤子敲击）
I DON'T GET IT.
我不明白。
I MADE MY HOUSE
A MESS
我做了我的房子
一团糟
WHICH WAS
MAKING IT CLEAN
哪个是
保持清洁
WHICH MADE SQUIDWARD
CLEAN MY YARD
章鱼哥的诞生
清洁我的院子
BUT THAT MEANS
HE'S MESSING IT UP.
但这意味着
他把事情搞砸了。
BUT THE OPPOSITE
OF CLEAN IS FILTH
但事实恰恰相反
清洁就是污秽
WHICH MEANS
FILTH IS CLEAN.
这意味着
污垢是干净的。
SQUIDWARD'S MAKING
MY YARD A WRECK
章鱼哥的制作
我的院子一片废墟
BUT I'D NORMALLY
WRECK MY OWN YARD
但我通常会
破坏我自己的院子
SO SQUIDWARD'S
BEING THE OPPOSITE
OF SQUIDWARD
所以章鱼哥的
相反
章鱼哥
WHICH MEANS
HE'S SPONGEBOB.
这意味着
他是海绵宝宝。
AHA! I UNDERSTAND
EVERYTHING NOW.
啊哈！我明白
现在一切。
I MUST BE THE OPPOSITE
OF SPONGEBOB BY BEING...
我一定是相反的
海绵宝宝的...
SQUIDWARD.
章鱼哥。
HEY...
嘿...
I WANT TO BE OPPOSITE, TOO.
我也想反对。
YEAH, FINALLY!
是的，终于！
YOO-HOO!
哟吼！
* I'M SQUIDWARD,
I'M SQUIDWARD *
*我是章鱼哥，
我是章鱼哥*
* SQUIDWARD, SQUIDWARD.
* 章鱼哥，章鱼哥。
WAIT.
等待。
IT'S NOT ENOUGH TO LOOK LIKE
SQUIDWARD TO BE OPPOSITE.
光是看起来还不够
章鱼哥在对面。
( imitating Squidward ):
YOU HAVE TO ACT LIKE HIM, TOO.
（模仿章鱼哥）：
你也必须像他一样行事。
BOY, OH, BOY, DO I LIKE
PLAYING THE CLARINET.
男孩，哦，男孩，我喜欢吗
演奏单簧管。
I PRACTICE AND PRACTICE
ALL DAY LONG
我练习再练习
一整天
BUT I NEVER GET ANY BETTER.
但我从来没有变得更好。
( in his own voice ):
NOW YOU TRY.
（用他自己的声音）：
现在你试试。
OKAY.
好的。
( inhales )
（吸气）
* I'M SQUIDWARD, SQUIDWARD,
SQUIDWARD, SQUIDWARD. *
* 我是章鱼哥，章鱼哥，
章鱼哥，章鱼哥。 *
Both:
* I'M SQUIDWARD, I'M SQUIDWARD
两者：
* 我是章鱼哥，我是章鱼哥
* SQUIDWARD, SQUIDWARD.
* 章鱼哥，章鱼哥。
AFTER YOU,
MR. SQUIDWARD.
在你之后，
先生。章鱼哥。
WHY, THANK YOU,
MR. SQUIDWARD.
为什么，谢谢，
先生。章鱼哥。
YOU'RE QUITE WELCOME,
MR. SQUIDWARD.
非常欢迎您，
先生。章鱼哥。
OPPOSITE DAY.
相反的一天。
NEXT TIME IT'S GOING TO BE
"GO JUMP OFF A CLIFF" DAY.
下次会是
“跳下悬崖”日。
( tires squeal )
（轮胎吱吱声）
OH, MY.
哦，我的。
THE HOUSE IS EVEN MORE BEAUTIFUL
IN PERSON.
房子更漂亮了
亲自。
HELLO, MIST...
你好，雾...
UM, MR. TENTACLES?
嗯，先生。触手？
YES, PLEASE COME IN.
是的，请进来。
I PICTURED YOU
BEING MUCH TALLER.
我描绘了你
长得更高了。
YEAH, EVERYONE
SAYS THAT.
是啊，大家
这么说。
NOW, IF YOU WANT
THE SALE TO GO THROUGH
现在，如果你愿意的话
待完成的出售
YOU'VE GOT TO TELL ME
你必须告诉我
ALL THE POSITIVE
THINGS ABOUT
YOUR HOUSE.
所有积极的一面
关于的事情
你的房子。
POSITIVE THINGS-- OPPOSITE DAY.
积极的事情——相反的一天。
I'D LOVE TO.
我喜欢。
THE FLOOR CREAKS,
THE ROOF LEAKS.
地板吱吱作响，
屋顶漏水。
THERE'S
A TERRIBLE DRAFT.
有
糟糕的草案。
UH... WELL, YOU DIDN'T
MENTION THAT ON THE PHONE.
呃...好吧，你没有
在电话中提及这一点。
PLEASE LET ME FINISH.
请让我说完。
THE WINTERS ARE HARD.
冬天很艰难。
THE SUMMERS ARE BRUTAL.
夏天是残酷的。
THERE'S A WILD MAN-EATING CLAM
IN THE BACKYARD.
有一种野生食人蛤
在后院。
WOULD YOU CARE TO SEE THE REST?
您想看看其余的吗？
WELL, I'M NOT SURE
IF I'M INTERESTED.
嗯，我不确定
如果我有兴趣的话。
NONSENSE.
废话。
I WON'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER.
我不会接受
寻求答案。
( honking )
（按喇叭）
PLEASE FOLLOW ME.
请跟我来。
AND HERE'S THE WORST ROOM
IN THE HOUSE: MY GALLERY.
这是最差的房间
在房子里：我的画廊。
OH, MY, THIS PAINTING
IS VERY NICE.
哦，天哪，这幅画
非常好。
THANK YOU.
( screams )
谢谢。
（尖叫声）
WHO'S THAT?
那是谁？
I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE
YOU TO MR. SQUIDWARD.
我想介绍一下
你对先生。章鱼哥。
YOU'RE BOTH SQUIDWARD?
你们都是章鱼哥？
I'M SQUIDWARD.
我是章鱼哥。
HE'S SQUIDWARD.
他是章鱼哥。
Both:
WE'RE BOTH SQUIDWARD.
两者：
我们都是章鱼哥。
( sighs )
（叹气）
WELL, THAT'S DONE.
好了，完成了。
AT LEAST SPONGEBOB
HAS BEEN QUIET.
至少海绵宝宝
一直很安静。
( screams ):
NO!
（尖叫声）：
不！
( playing squeakily )
（玩得吱吱作响）
OKAY, I REALLY
DON'T WANT TO
HEAR ANOTHER ONE.
好吧，我真的
不想
听听另一首。
OKAY.
好的。
( tooting )
（嘟嘟）
I REALLY DON'T
WANT TO HEAR MORE,
THANK YOU.
我真的不知道
想听更多，
谢谢。
I HEAR YOU
LOUD AND CLEAR.
我听到你的声音
响亮而清晰。
( tooting )
（嘟嘟）
Squidward:
STOP!
章鱼哥：
停下来！
GET AWAY FROM HER!
离她远点！
OH, OH, I AM SO SORRY, MA'AM.
哦，哦，我很抱歉，女士。
I-I HOPE THESE
TWO BARNACLE-HEADS
我-我希望这些
两个藤壶头
HAVEN'T HARMED YOU IN ANY WAY.
没有以任何方式伤害你。
WHO ARE YOU?
你是谁？
WHY, I'M SQUIDWARD.
为什么，我是章鱼哥。
WHAT KIND OF FOOL
DO YOU TAKE ME FOR?
什么样的傻瓜
你把我当成是吗？
HE'S SQUIDWARD?
他是章鱼哥？
YOU'RE SQUIDWARD?
你是章鱼哥？
I'M SQUIDWARD!
我是章鱼哥！
ARE THERE ANY
OTHER SQUIDWARDS?
有吗
其他章鱼哥？
( in Squidward's voice ):
MEOW.
（用章鱼哥的声音）：
喵。
I'M OUT OF HERE.
我要离开这里了。
MA'AM, PLEASE.
女士，请。
WHAT ABOUT MY HOUSE?
我的房子呢？
I WOULDN'T SELL A HOUSE FOR YOU
我不会为你卖房子
IF YOU WERE
THE LAST SQUIDWARD ON EARTH!
如果你是
地球上最后一个章鱼哥！
WAIT!
等待！
DON'T...
不...
GO!
去！
( screams )
（尖叫声）
NO, NO, NO!
不，不，不！
PLEASE SELL MY HOUSE.
请卖掉我的房子。
NEVER!
绝不！
DON'T LEAVE ME HERE!
别把我留在这里！
( crying )
（哭）
Both:
HAPPY OPPOSITE DAY, SQUIDWARD.
两者：
快乐的相反的一天，章鱼哥。
WE HATE YOU.
我们恨你。
LET ME SHOW YOU GUYS
HOW MUCH I HATE YOU.
让我给你们展示一下
我多么恨你。
( engine revs )
（发动机转速）
( yelling )
（大喊）
PATRICK, YOU EVER FEEL
帕特里克，你曾经有过这样的感觉
THAT SQUIDWARD
LIKES US TOO MUCH?
那个章鱼哥
太喜欢我们了？
HAPPY OPPOSITE DAY!
对面的日子快乐！
[Captioning sponsored by THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
[字幕由THE赞助
美国教育部
and NICKELODEON]
和尼克频道]
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]
[标题为
字幕中心
WGBH教育基金会]
[标题为
字幕中心
WGBH教育基金会]